<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
  <channel>
    <title>Twin Maps</title>
    <link>http://www.twinmaps.com</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <ttl>40</ttl>
    <description></description>
        
        <item>
          <title>Twin Maps - Final Feature</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;...for indeed, the kingdom of God is within you.&amp;quot; Luke 17:21&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twin Maps presents our final feature! This is a presentation of our story, our journey, and our adventure. We traveled all across America and have this to show for it. Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to thank the United Church of Christ Volunteer Ministries for sponsoring this incredible journey and for trusting two kids with cameras. We'd also like to thank our parents; without them, this project would have never happened.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we would especially like to thank you, the viewer, for keeping up with our travels throughout this year.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;610&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/26543156?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&amp;amp;autoplay=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;610&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/WpZLXaWQPgw?hd=1&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 21:00:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/409608-twin-maps-final-feature</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/409608-twin-maps-final-feature</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Synod Wrap Up, Final Numbers, and What's Next</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;There are those who give with joy, and that joy is their reward.&amp;quot; Kahlil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we sit here in our living room of China Grove, NC, reminiscing of our trip with our parents, we are reminded of the many gifts that we were given on this journey. And one of the greatest gifts was our time in Tampa at General Synod.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We screened our feature again on July 4th in the exhibit hall and then we had two more presentations. The first was for a dinner with Wider Church Ministries. The second was for the morning plenary on July 5th. We spoke about our time traveling and how supporting our churches and communities make a positive impact in our lives. For a more eloquent rendition of what we said, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ucc.org/news/brooke-brothers-thank-ocwm-in.html&quot;&gt;I turn your attention to this article that was written by Jeff Woodard&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drive back to North Carolina was different to say the least. We didn't talk much about our journey, more about our futures and what was next. It was a strange feeling, knowing that this was the last time we would be traveling together for this project. The experience was surreal and life-altering and we have the rest of our lives and futures to thank because of the Twin Maps project. We will not consider this project finished until we complete the shorter features from the rest of our journey. While this may take a while, we are determined and invigorated to finish it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after we catch up on all our features, we are still going to continue the Twin Maps project in some form. It won't be the same journey or experience, but we are currently trying to plan our next move. Stay tuned and you'll hear more about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Concerning our futures, we have jobs. Both of us. We will actually be working together. We will be Associate Producers for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.raycomsports.com/&quot;&gt;Raycom Sports&lt;/a&gt; in Charlotte, NC. Yes, we are working for the same company. Yes, we are going to live in the same apartment. We are even sharing an office for the present time... Joy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Again, we are speaking at Catawba College on Friday, July 15 in Salisbury, NC at 6:45 pm. If you're in the area, you should come. After that, we will be uploading our Synod Feature to Twin Maps.com for everyone to see.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We would like to thank everyone that's joined us on this journey. Without your help and support, this would not have been possible. Thank you for everything and we hope you continue to follow us and wherever this project takes us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final Numbers/Information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miles Driven: 17,000 miles. (Rough Estimate)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;States Worked: 21, plus DC (North Carolina, Ohio, West Virginia, Maryland, Washington DC, New York, Massachusetts, Pennsylvania, Missouri, Tennessee, Arizona, Texas, California, Oregon, Washington, South Dakota, Iowa, Illinois, Kentucky, Mississippi, Louisiana, Florida)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;States Driven Through but not worked: 15 (Virginia, Delaware, New Jersey, Connecticut, Indiana, Arkansas, Oklahoma, New Mexico, Idaho, Wyoming, Nebraska, Wisconson, Alabama, Georgia, South Carolina)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;States Missed Altogether: 14 (Maine, New Hampshire, Rhode Island, Vermont, Michigan, Kansas, Minnesota, North Dakota, Colorado, Utah, Montana, Nevada, Alaska, Hawaii)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most popular song on our iPod: &amp;quot;Teenage Dream&amp;quot; by Katy Perry. (We're not kidding about this)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most overbought item: Water Bottles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most common food consumed: Peanut Butter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times we ate at McDonalds/Burger King/Taco Bell/KFC/Long John Silvers/Hardee's/Carl's Jr/Bojangles/And countless other fast food joints: 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times we ate at In-N-Out Burger: 1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Times we ate at Subway: Countless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of lenses broken: 2&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil Changes: 4 (oops)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flat Tires: 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speeding Tickets: 0&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number of One-Time Paralell Parking jobs: 3&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friends from past lives met along the way: 20&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Friends and New Memories made: Countless&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again everyone! Look forward to posting the feature on July 16th!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 21:13:11 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/397554-synod-wrap-up-final-numbers-and</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/397554-synod-wrap-up-final-numbers-and</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Updates from Synod</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Life isn't about finding yourself. Life is about creating yourself.&amp;quot; - George Bernard Shaw&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greetings from Tampa, Florida!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are live and well here at UCC General Synod 28 in Tampa! What an incredible experience so far! We've caught up with people from our trip, had reunions as we've worked, and made new friends as we've experienced Synod in all of its splendor! We're staying with the Youth at General Synod so we've made a great connection with so many of the talented and promising youth here!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We even have a video of a flash mob they did!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;1280&quot; height=&quot;750&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ETkhYut6DxI?hd=1&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Thursday, we presented our first screening for our final feature. We presented to the Youth at Synod. We had a fantastic audience that was engaging and incredibly interested in how volunteers are helping out their communities. This week, the youth are volunteering at neighborhood organizations throughout Tampa. They've worked at animal shelters, poverty centers, and city enrichment programs. So our program was geared toward that message and we believe it was well-received.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will still be presenting our final feature on Monday, July 4th at 10:30 am at the Exhibit Hall for UCC General Synod. We will also be speaking at the Tuesday morning session about our travels. Also, Catawba College on July 15th in the evening in Salisbury, NC will be our final screening. Be there!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Catawba on the 15th, we will upload the final feature to the internet for everyone to see! For those asking, we will still continue to produce smaller features for the sites that we visited. We will not consider this project finished until they are done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all for now! See everyone at Synod!&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2011 03:51:19 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/392273-updates-from-synod</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/392273-updates-from-synod</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Ride With Larry</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Art enables us to find ourselves and lose ourselves at the same time.&amp;quot; - Thomas Merton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along our journey, we met incredible people. They stand out in different ways and have taken a part of our hearts with them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One person, however, impacted us deeply... And we never met him personally.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While staying in Carlsbad, CA, we lived with Caroline and Micheal Theiss-Aird. They were kind, welcoming, and incredible hosts. While speaking about our project with them, their thought immediately turned to Caroline's Brother-In-Law, Larry Smith, a baker from south Dakota.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The thing about Larry, though, is that he has Parkinson's disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The special thing about him, is that he doesn't let it hold him back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From anything.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, Larry, along with our hosts Carolina and Michael, is biking across the state of South Dakota. They end their journey this weekend in Vermillion, SD. He has been biking for years and a film crew is documenting his journey.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;400&quot; height=&quot;225&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/15533022?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/15533022&quot;&gt;Ride with Larry (trailer)&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/ridewithlarry&quot;&gt;Ride with Larry&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excerpt from the film's website:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em style=&quot;padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; &quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Ride with Larry&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a feature length documentary that puts a human face on the day-to-day fight against Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s through the story of Larry Smith, a retired police captain, now beloved small-town baker. After twenty years with the Parkinson&amp;rsquo;s, Larry plans to bike across his state of South Dakota in the Spring of 2011 with the support of his family and community to show the power of keeping your body active and mind positive, proving that the best cure is living life to its fullest.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ridewithlarrymovie.com&quot;&gt;RideWithLarryMovie.com&lt;/a&gt; for more information and to support this incredible journey.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2011 04:16:57 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/374711-ride-with-larry</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/374711-ride-with-larry</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Dates for the Final Feature</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;God forgives those who invent what they need.&amp;quot; - Lillian Herman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently in New Orleans, LA. We're covering the Disaster Recovery Project here in tandem with Little Farms UCC. But we've also been slaving away to finish our Final Feature for General Synod on time. Because of the time the feature is taking, We've halted all production on the other locations that we've visited and captured. Production for them will resume after General Synod 2011.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll be presenting our final feature in three locations. The first two are at General Synod in Tampa Florida.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 30. 7:30 pm. Howard Johnson Hotel. Crown Ballroom. Tampa, Florida. Youth at General Synod Presentation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 4. 10:30 am. Tampa Bay Convention Center. Tampa, Florida. Exhibit Hall Convention.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;July 15. 6:45 pm. Catawba College Auditorium. Salisbury, North Carolina. Church Youth Empowerment Weekend.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be screening our final feature, along with a presentation of our journey and growth, to the audience in attendance. After we've presented on July 15th, we will upload the video to the internet so that everyone can see it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While this is certainly no end to the TwinMaps project, we've had an amazing and successful trip. As the week progresses, expect a large number of updates from us as we reflect and remember this incredible experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers guys!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2011 07:43:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/371456-dates-for-the-final-feature</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/371456-dates-for-the-final-feature</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>&quot;Dear America&quot; - A Twin Maps Trailer</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Yesterday is but today's memory; tomorrow is today's dream.&amp;quot; - Kahlil Gibran&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have created a trailer for our upcoming feature to be shown at General Synod. This feature gives you just a small taste of what to expect from our final product.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://player.vimeo.com/video/24402425?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;350&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/24402425&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;Dear America&amp;quot; - Twin Maps Trailer&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com/user4721457&quot;&gt;Twin Maps&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href=&quot;http://vimeo.com&quot;&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will be showing our encompassing feature at Youth at General Synod in Tampa on June 30 and also at Catawba College on July 15th. Afterwards, we'll find a way to get the feature up and online.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'd like to take this time to thank everyone who made this trip possible. This is not the last &amp;quot;Thank You&amp;quot; you shall receive either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those of you who prefer YouTube, here's the trailer in that format.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;349&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/grOGLqy-R7M&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Memorial Day everyone!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2011 06:11:55 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/349411-dear-america-a-twin-maps</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/349411-dear-america-a-twin-maps</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>CJ and Joey</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;God places the heaviest burden on those who can carry the weight.&amp;quot; - Reggie Jackson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We experienced probably the most special moment of this trip today.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roxanne, a case manager at Back Bay Mission, agreed to take us on a trip around Biloxi today. Every week, she visits with people in the streets of Biloxi, who she works with to better their lives. Her rounds today included a trip into apartments with old friends, the streets for a soup kitchen, and even into the woods to find people who were living in tents.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But one story really stuck out to us today as traveled with Roxanne.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked into an apartment and Roxanne introduced us to a single mother and daughter who lived there. They were living in a one-bedroom apartment, but the apartment they were living in was packed with more trinkets, books, pillows, blankets, and other accessories than they care to admit. CJ, the mother, had moved her bed into the living room which made it difficult to navigate while living there. Her daughter, Joey, had the bedroom to herself, but it had become more designated storage space than it was a bedroom. CJ lost her husband while she was pregnant with Joey, so they only had each other. Ever since Joey was born they had either been homeless or lived in that apartment. From the moment you were around them, you could tell that their relationship had seen hard times and even harder struggles; however, their resilience kept them together and strong.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roxanne had good news for them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They were going to move into a two-bedroom apartment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The room was instantly filled with squeals of glee and laughter. CJ and Joey embraced Roxanne and nearly knocked her over. Their original dour mood was instantly lifted and they were all smiles from the rest of the time we were there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What a feeling to witness. Growing up in a well-provided home, we did not want for much when we were younger. Sure, we could have wanted that extra piece of candy or the new toy fad, but never ran out of any essentials. Our home was accommodating, we had close friends and a family that loved us. We always had more than enough and never needed any more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not this family. They have struggled. But they struggled together. After strapping down, working hard, finding help, and being resilient, they now have a chance to move into a two bedroom apartment. To some, this may not be a big deal. But to CJ and Joey, it's huge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I haven't had my own bedroom since... since before you were born!&amp;quot; CJ said to Joey. Both laugh.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They sat down to speak with us. Joey's been doing well in school since they have a home now. She wants to be a photojournalist when she grows up. CJ smiles. You can feel the love in the room as they speak with each other. They recounted how hard it was to live after Katrina hit. Their original home was gone and they had to find couches in homes to sleep on. It was pretty rough for them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/CJ and Joey.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We say our goodbyes and exchange contact information. We hope to hear from them soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walk out the door, we hear the squeals and joy resume. You can tell how happy they are. Roxanne laughs, shakes her head and says:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;That's the best part of my job.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2011 05:36:07 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/344325-cj-and-joey</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/344325-cj-and-joey</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Biloxi, Back Bay Mission, and Katrina</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Don't ask what the world needs. Ask what makes you come alive, and go do it. Because what the world needs is people who have come alive.&amp;quot; Howard Thurman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to beautiful, sunny, Biloxi, Mississippi!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven't yet, go &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFHvnLSgOgw&quot;&gt;listen to our podcast&lt;/a&gt;. Because if you don't, you are going to be totally lost on where we have been and what we've been up to since our last major update. Seriously, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vFHvnLSgOgw&quot;&gt;go listen to it&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the month of May, we are here in Biloxi. We are working and staying with the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thebackbaymission.org/&quot;&gt;Back Bay Mission&lt;/a&gt;, an organization that serves the poor and marginalized in the Gulf by providing all types of services ranging from day shelter services to building homes. Since Katrina in 2005, their mission has been increasingly involved with construction and repair of homes. They have groups that come in from all across the United States to help in the Micah Center, a day shelter that allows the impoverished to shower and do their laundry, and to help rebuild homes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While filming here, we're going to be helping with their mission.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Hurricane Katrina hit the Gulf on August 29, 2005, it nearly took Biloxi with it. For many years after Katrina, there were just slabs of concrete and foundation on beach front properties, outlining restaurants, businesses, and homes that used to occupy them. We drove around with Craig, the construction director, who gave us a tour of the area.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The eastern part of Biloxi is incredibly poor. The further west, and closer to Keesler Air Force Base, you travel, the less poverty you see. But one thing stays constant: beach front property is minimal. Most of it was destroyed. You drive along the streets of Biloxi and see front steps that lead to no where.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard is going to be acting as the Volunteer Coordinator, the person who sets and and hosts the arriving groups. Max is volunteering as the Micah Center Associate, the point person for day-to-day activities of the Micah Center. We will be doing this in addition to filming and, on other days, will be out helping on the work site.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also have to focus on our Feature that we will be presenting at General Synod...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That last line was difficult to write... Because once Syond is over, we're done with this assignment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn't over yet... But it's getting close.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2011 13:49:03 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/331345-biloxi-back-bay-mission-and-katrina</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/331345-biloxi-back-bay-mission-and-katrina</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Twin Maps Podcast for 5-5-2011</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I have been impressed with the urgency of doing. Knowing is not enough; we must apply. Being willing is not enough; we must do.&amp;quot; Leonardo da Vinci&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a Podcast! We've never done one before, but it sounded like fun and we wanted to try it out. Also, it seemed like a cool way to convey what we've been doing since we left Re-Member earlier in April. If you like this format, we may keep doing it for updates. It was fun to create it and we got the chance to be a little less formal with this update.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here's our podcast! Enjoy!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;510&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/vFHvnLSgOgw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2011 13:51:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/326547-twin-maps-podcast-for-5-5-2011</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/326547-twin-maps-podcast-for-5-5-2011</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Toksa: Saying Good-Bye to Re-Member</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Don't wait. The timing will never be just right.&amp;quot; Napoleon Hill&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Badlands&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;/badlands.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;The Badlands and part of Katie's head.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leaving the Pine Ridge Reservation was tough for us.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For one, we left on Tuesday, April 19th, in the middle of the work week. We had gotten to know the two groups of high school students that were working on the Reservation that week. They were all smart, driven, compassionate, and fearless... A deadly combination... They reminded us of how we were at that age. We got to know the staff at Re-Member. They were concerned, knowledgable, and from all walks of life. They provided many stories about life on the Rez, knowledge and awareness, and where to go from here. When you talk to the staff about what keeps them on the Rez, they always talk about a single moment that sticks out to them: a moment with a native, seeing nature in its purest form, helping others grow... Any life altering moment that changes your core. We had seen the Oglala Lakota people, speaking about their culture, their heritage, and their future. They are incredible people and have an incredible sense of community and family. We got the chance to see this when we filmed on Monday. We had to split up to cover their many projects. Richard was on site at a work crew who was skirting a mobile home. Max traveled with a food distribution truck that delivered food all across the Reservation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Man Reaching for an Apple&quot; src=&quot;/man reaching for apple.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&amp;nbsp;During snow, food distribution was handed out at Porcupine.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Girls with Other Girls&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; src=&quot;/girls with smaller girls.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;Part of the Re-Member Group with the Red Shirt Girls&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students were the best. They soaked every moment up, genuinely wanted to help people, and made friends with kids they had never met before. At times, they would say the exact things that we were thinking. It was incredibly refreshing to be around students again. We felt their energy, their shock, their passion, and their courage, and it overflowed into our work.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Lecture&quot; src=&quot;/Long shot of campers.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&amp;nbsp;Morning Wisdom with Ted and group&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;Don't fall asleep around Max&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; src=&quot;/katie asleep.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;Don't fall asleep in a car with Max&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;address&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we had to leave all of that midweek.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know we had an itinerary to keep, and we had to move on to the next project, but leaving Re-Member felt premature; it was as if we were leaving a flower before it had fully blossomed. The students were making real connections with the people on the Reservation, life-altering work was being accomplished, and relationships were being made that will last lifetimes. We can't help but feel as if we were meant to be there for the long haul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;Ted and Resident&quot; src=&quot;/ted and resident.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;Ted, the director of Re-member, talking to one of the men from Red Shirt&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian Reservations in the United States are overlooked. They are not talked about, they are pushed aside, they are kept silent. But the interesting thing about the reservation citizens is that they&amp;nbsp;&lt;em style=&quot;margin-top: 0px; margin-right: 0px; margin-bottom: 0px; margin-left: 0px; padding-top: 0px; padding-right: 0px; padding-bottom: 0px; padding-left: 0px; border-top-width: 0px; border-right-width: 0px; border-bottom-width: 0px; border-left-width: 0px; border-style: initial; border-color: initial; font-weight: inherit; font-style: italic; font-size: 12px; font-family: inherit; vertical-align: baseline; &quot;&gt;want&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;to be left alone. They don't want the US government interfering with their lives, they don't want an Americanized culture, and they certainly don't want any white people coming in and telling them how they should live... That has been the case for the better part of 400 years and they are tired of it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's almost fitting that we felt that way about leaving Pine Ridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on the Reservation is never done.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took a lesson from the Reservation with us in our travels.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And we WILL be back.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no doubt about that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;700&quot; height=&quot;467&quot; alt=&quot;We'll be back&quot; src=&quot;/with some of the girls at the end.jpg&quot; /&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;address&gt;From left to right: Jean, a volunteer from Ireland, Richard, Katie, Max, and Charli&lt;/address&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Name: South Dakota&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital: Pierre&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nickname: The Mount Rushmore State&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flower: &lt;a href=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/b/ba/Pulsatilla_vulgaris-700px.jpg&quot;&gt;Pasque Flower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Motto: &amp;quot;Under God the people rule.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flag:&amp;nbsp;&lt;img width=&quot;720&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/South Dakota Flag.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2011 06:06:37 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/319689-toksa-saying-good-bye-to-re-member</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/319689-toksa-saying-good-bye-to-re-member</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Mitakuye Oyasin: Paying our Respects at Wounded Knee</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We're here&amp;quot;, Bryan, our bus driver and one of our guides said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We looked out the window and saw what we had driven to see: stone fixtures, dirt paths, unkept gates, all on top of an eerily overcast hill.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had arrived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wounded Knee, South Dakota.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The students from Shabazz City High School in Madison, WI filed out accordingly, zipping up their jackets as they dove head first into the rain. We stayed behind and started to pack up our cameras. We wanted to see the Wounded Knee Cemetary, where all pay their respects to the departed of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wounded_Knee_Massacre&quot;&gt;two&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wounded_Knee_incident&quot;&gt;massacres&lt;/a&gt;; however, we couldn't use our cameras in the rain. We were not happy, and when we exited the bus, our guides noticed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Can't use your cameras in the rain?&amp;quot; Dan, a volunteer from Ireland questioned.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We told him we couldn't.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;That's too bad.&amp;quot; said Jean, Dan's wife. &amp;quot;I imagine you could get good shots up there.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left the staff members who had seen Wounded Knee before and started the long, slow trek up the hill, cursing the bad luck we had with the weather.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we walked up the hill towards Wounded Knee, the rain fell and our thoughts drifted back to what we had learned earlier upon our arrival to South Dakota.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The organization we were filming, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.re-member.org/&quot;&gt;Re-Member&lt;/a&gt;, is located in Pine Ridge, South Dakota. They work with the Oglala Lakota Indian Reservation, whose land mass is roughly the size of Connecticut. They immerse groups of youth and adults into work projects on the reservation so they can rebuild relationships, homes and lives. They have been working the Reservation for 14 years, and have needed every single year to gain the trust of the tribe. We had never been on an Indian Reservation before, so we didn't know what to expect and had no way to prepare for the reservation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian Reservations are ... complicated to say the least. Most reservations have &amp;quot;tribal sovereignty&amp;quot; which allows the tribal leadership to establish and execute its laws, customs, and practices. They are bound by some federal and state laws, but not all. Because of this, each tribe has its own culture and customs that can be confusing to visitors who are unaware of them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we first stepped on the reservation, we knew that we had entered a different land. We were two of the very few white people on the reservation. Wherever we went, we always had the sensation of being watched and judged by everyone, as if wiser eyes were viewing us with uneasiness. We never felt unsafe, but we did feel as if we didn't belong.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hard to blame Native Americans for not trusting someone with white skin.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;***&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With our equipment burdening us, we reached the top of the hill. Ted, the director of Re-Member, had set up for a local to speak about the importance of Wounded Knee to the reservation. The students, who were educated in the history of the massacre, listened ardently. Each of them, including us, had to stare this tragedy in the eye and realize the bloody history that came with it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain continued to fall. It drenched a small, American flag that was on the muddy ground. It had been placed in a nearby fence to commemorate a fallen friend, and had fallen from its place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were allowed to walk into the cemetary. The students, who had previously been so lively and full of spirit, walked slowly and somberly in the cemetary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We followed in and paid our respects.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rain began to pick up. Our speaker, who had arrived by car to the top of the hill, bid us farewell and drove off. We started the long trek down the hill.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman in the group saw the American flag. She picked it up, wiped off what mud she could, and placed it back into the fence... A small step towards recovery.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we reached the bottom of the hill, we were bombarded with local artists attempting to sell crafts to our group. Under normal conditions, we would brush all advances off. The reservation, however, has a 90% unemployment rate. The craftsmen here were not looking to rip off tourists who didn't know better, they were looking to find a way to feed their family that night.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all filed into the bus, turned around on the dirt road, and drove back to our camp for the week.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have work to do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2011 05:42:05 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/312865-mitakuye-oyasin-paying-our-respects-at</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/312865-mitakuye-oyasin-paying-our-respects-at</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Washington and South Dakota are not close to each other</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In the middle of difficulty lies opportunity.&amp;quot; Albert Einstein&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's play a little catch up, shall we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We departed from White Swan, WA on Wednesday, April 13. We had to travel to Pocatello, ID for the night. We started the drive; however, we had to stop and take a phone call for One Great Hour of Sharing (OGHS) Live this past Wednesday night. We spoke about our project and what it means for the furture of volunteer work. We did all of this outside of Bronco Stadium in Boise, ID, which is an iconic college football stadium.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After arriving (late) in Pocatello, we caught up on sleep, and set out on the road again. We started our trek through Wyoming and even saw some Elk. Wyoming, by the way, is one of the most beautiful states in the country to drive through. We were lucky enough to drive through both Jackson, WY and the Grand Teton National Park, so the scenery was stunning. The strange mix between snow and great plains was a gorgeous contrast.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The snow, however, did throw a wrench into our plans. Snow from Nebraska did deter us from arriving in Pine Ridge, SD on time. We had to stop in Chadron, NE and bunk up there for the evening.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friday morning came, and we arrived in Pine Ridge, SD for Re-Member.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've had an awful long days of traveling, and even after a nap we're still exhausted.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here are state facts for Washington, and we're off to bed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Night all!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State: Washington&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nickname: The Evergreen State&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital: Olympia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motto: Alki (Trans. &amp;quot;Eventually&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flower: Coast Rhohodendron&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flag:&amp;nbsp;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;/washington state flag.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 07:49:09 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/307554-washington-and-south-dakota-are-not</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/307554-washington-and-south-dakota-are-not</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>The Disaster Recovery Project Feature is Posted!!!</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The excursion is the same when you go looking for your sorrow as when you go looking for joy.&amp;quot; Eudora Welty&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most overlooked story in the United States this past year occurred while we were graduating college.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of May, Middle Tennessee was hit with the worst flooding in its recorded history. Locals and reporters alike began to call it the &amp;quot;Thousand-Year Flood.&amp;quot; For good reason too. The damages the flood left, both monetarily and spiritually, have left holes in the city of Nashville that have yet to be refilled.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While covering the Disaster Recovery Project in December, 7 months removed from the disaster, we caught the city and its victims in a strange place between recovery and normalcy. Everyone who we spoke with had a different story to tell. Margaret Parrish lost her car and had to clean out her basement. Char Creson's house was flooded and had to remove her floor and walls, but still lives in the same home. In Lisa Morrison's case, however, she had to abandon her home entirely, leaving her house with only the clothes on her back and her family in her arms.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city was left devastated, but Tennesseans responded the way the Volunteer state should.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They rallied around each other.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Nashville floods didn't get much national coverage, because the locals didn't steal, or loot, or destroy... they helped recover.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, throughout all this, they still need our help. Hundreds still have not returned to their homes and hundreds more need help with their repairs. They are recovering, but it is a slow process.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feature was created to show two things: the devastation that was caused and the work that still needs to be done. We will never be able to do justice to the tales of survival that were told to us and the thousands more that are in the area. We can only hope that this feature gives you a slight glimpse into what is was like for most Tennesseans during the flood.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/P9X-fJLuPKQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2011 09:16:41 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/304538-the-disaster-recovery-project-feature-is</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/304538-the-disaster-recovery-project-feature-is</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>The Top Ten Things We've Learned Since Starting Twin Maps</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We may encounter many defeats, but we must not be defeated.&amp;quot; Maya Angelou&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blogging to you live, from White Swan, Washington, Twin Maps is back on the road!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past two weeks, we've been on break. We wrapped up filming in Seattle and started our break by flying back home to North Carolina. We left our car with family in Seattle so the Kia could keep some miles off of her, and when we arrived back home, we were happily surrounded with family, friends, and love. We caught up with old acquaintances, saw some life-long friends, and made time for our closest friends and family in a (very) quick two weeks. It's over now and we're back on the road and have a busy few weeks ahead of us. We're currently on assignment in White Swan, WA covering the Yakama Christian Mission. Over the next 4 weeks, will be in South Dakota, Nebraska, Iowa, Illinois, Kentucky, and Mississippi. It's going to be a very busy month ahead of us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before we dive into our third and final leg of our trip, we want to share with you one of our favorite moments from our time back home. We were scheduled to give a presentation at our church, Mt. Zion UCC in China Grove, NC, for Sunday School. However, our pastor woke up sick the same morning and could not make it to church. Our church leadership has handled a situation like this with much grace before, so it was a surprise when they asked us if we could deliver the message. We accepted, and decided that we would take a portion of our presentation from earlier that morning and dive into more detail.   We talked about the Top Ten Things that we have learned while traveling with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We wanted to recreate this list for our readers here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;10. Gas Prices are expensive... Everywhere!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter where you go, who you talk to, what part of the country you're in, gas prices are devilishly high. They affect everyone, everywhere and everyone complains about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;9. When you give, you receive more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a lesson that we learned very early in our travels. Wherever we traveled, we met a group of selfless, committed people who gave their talents, intelligence, ambitions and fortunes to the betterment of society and their neighbors. When asked why they did things for their community, the answer was always the same: &amp;quot;Whenever we help others, we help ourselves. What we get out of helping others is greater than the help we can give to others.&amp;quot; Volunteers have this attitude wherever we go. It is thankless and special.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;8. It is a challenge to do professional work with your brother.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it's even worse when you're twins. We didn't go to the same University, so after four years of being apart, we had to (quickly) learn how to work together again. It wasn't without its speedbumps, but we think we got the hang of it now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7. The next story is always different from the last.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this trip, we have visited countless homeless shelters, transitional living centers, volunteer corps, and services to the poor. You would think that eventually these places would have the same stories over and over again; eventually, we'd fall a cycle of monotony when covering another shelter. But that's the exact opposite of what we've found. Once you get beyond the statistics and actually get to know the people you're covering, you find unique personality and people no matter where we are. We get to approach each story with fresh eyes every time, and it's because we work with some of the strongest and bravest people we have ever met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. If you ever want us to do anything for you, just bribe us with food.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's kind of like college.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. There is always a need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever a person says that they &amp;quot;want to make a difference,&amp;quot; some thoughts immediately turn to international need. Who can blame them? Africa is a war-torn continent, the Middle-East is in turmoil, and disaster recovery is needed every time a catastrophe occurs. But, as we have found out, the most immediate and influential impact a person can make is in their community. You can find a need within a five mile radius of your home, and you will grow and advance your community in ways you may have thought impossible. Get out there, find a problem, volunteer, and make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. The maturity level of a 23 year old American and a 20 year old German are the exact same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While traveling, we have had the pleasure of living/working/spending time with Germans who are volunteering in the United States. We have more in common with them than we thought, as we talk, think, act, and do the same things that they do. We're glad that we have gained brothers and sisters from across borders on this trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Always be in the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one that is bittersweet for us. Whenever we travel, we know that our time is limited and fleeting with those around us. We have to always make sure that we leave a good impression, but we also want to make a real connection with people. We need interaction, growth, and connection with the people around us. Every single thing you do with a person is important: every conversation, every action, every nuance. Because you don't know how long or how short your time is with a person, and that moment could be the last time you ever see that person. You never know what type of impression someone will make on your lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Two guys traveling/living in a car for an entire year makes for a smelly car.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not much more needs to be said about that one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. There is so much good in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever you turn on the news, you hear a story about how the world is suffering. Poverty is on the rise, crime is up, politicians are corrupt and your neighborhood isn't safe anymore. There isn't much hope for a world whose people are not inherently good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While on this trip, we've seen the exact opposite. We've seen the good in people shine through the tough times that are ahead of them. We've seen people overcome struggles to attain a better life. We've seen people sacrifice their talents, time, and fortune just to give their neighbor a hand. There are good people in this world, and they want to be agents of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project is meant to highlight volunteer work throughout the United States; we want to capture ordinary people actively changing their communities around them. At a deeper level, however, we want to see people for how they really are. And in our travels, we have met people that want to experience the world in a real and raw way. They want to see people as they are, not how society paints them. They want to experience God in an undiluted way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For every bit of evil in this world, there is good. For every inkling of fear, there is courage and kindness. For every bit of hate, there is love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can only hope that our work reflects what we have seen. At the end of it all, if we only show reflections of love, then Twin Maps has been successful.&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 07:31:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/297304-the-top-ten-things-we-ve-learned</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/297304-the-top-ten-things-we-ve-learned</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Church World Service Feature!!!</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Victory is won not in miles but in inches. Win a little now, hold your ground, and later, win a little more.&amp;quot; - Louis L'Amour&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The video for Church World Service is posted!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Church World Service: Immigration and Resettlement Programs is located in Lancaster, Pennsylvania. Their primary mission is to aid in the transition and resettlement of refugees who seek safe asylum from their home country. Whenever a citizen of a country fears for their life, due to corrupt governments threatening their livelihood, they can apply for refugee status through the United Nations. Once granted, they may relocate to another country quickly. The concern with many refugees, however, is how they will acclimate and adapt to their new environment. This is where CWS comes in. They are a guiding hand for the thousands of refugees that travel to the United States each year. They walk them through the refugee process, connect them with family in the U.S., provide ESL classes, and provide a safe haven of community.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our time with CWS was a cherished one. We learned about our country, how we take in more refugees than any other country in the world. We learned about our neighbors, how sometimes you have to look a little deeper to gain an understanding of them. We learned about ourselves, about how we really don't know anything when it comes to reality outside of the US.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, most importantly, we learned about hospitality. We learned that even when you have next to nothing, you can still put a smile on, and enjoy the company around you.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's the easiest way to dispel fear: help each other out. A simple, but lasting lesson that has been a theme of this trip.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the feature!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;390&quot; src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/ca2iAEUzQJM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are currently on our two week break from travel. We flew back to North Carolina and are currently enjoying our time with family and friends. We will be back on the road starting April 4th.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, we have created a bracket for the NCAA tournament. Yes, it is already busted. No, we are not cheering for Duke.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks everyone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2011 16:35:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/285546-church-world-service-feature</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/285546-church-world-service-feature</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>The Crest of the U-Turn</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This time, like all times, is a good time, if we but know what to do with it.&amp;quot; Ralph Waldo Emerson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, we are in Port Orchard, Washington. If you were to draw a straight line between here and our hometown of China Grove, NC we would be 2,322 miles away from home. This will be the furthest away we will be from our hometown. We did a check on Google Maps, and it turns out that it would take us nearly 45 hours of driving to return home.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're a long way from home... But we're at the end of the U-Turn.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've changed since we departed North Carolina in September. We've changed even moreso since departing from Christmas Break in January. When we started this trip, we told ourselves that we were merely avoiding &amp;quot;real-world responsibilities&amp;quot;, capitializing on our youth, and feeding our American sentiments to wander into the world without a whim or care. Don't get us wrong, these things still hold true. The thought of pencil-pushing in a job still terrifies us. We don't want a career that isn't meaningful and will leave us dissatisfied. We also wanted to take advantage of our youth. There is nothing more beautiful than being young, we tell ourselves. After this, there will be no chance in our lives to emulate an experience like this. We don't have anything holding us back, save for the limitations we put on ourselves. And we are feeding an American sentiment: traveling in a car across the country. We Americans are sojourners by virtue of our roots. We have an insatiable desire to see the world for what it really is: a raw, powerful, awe-inspiring experience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That much hasn't changed. But you know what has? Our relationship with each other, our views on homelessness, on poverty, on immigrants, on the mentally ill, on political systems, on media and its control, on traveling, on sports, on our purchasing habits, on Americans, on what we want to do after we're done, on everything really. We knew that this would be a life-altering experience, and as we sprint past the halfway point, our metamorphosis is already measureable. We've learned to appreciate the company around us, whether we spend a week with them or a few fleeting moments before we disappear forever. We realize the liklihood of us seeing someone from this trip again is, under normal circumstances, slim to none.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we are not normal people.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And neither is anyone we've met on this trip.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The people we've met want to be a part of something real. They want to experience God on a personal level. They want for those around them to grow in a positive way. They want their communities to be agents of good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They want the world around them to be affected in ways it previously thought impossible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This attitude is not limited to volunteers either. Most Americans feel this way. We want to see the world around us become the productive environment we know it can be. We want those in need to be stripped of their sufferings. We want people to love each other. That's the true spirit of American spirit: adventure, self-growth and helping your fellow man. It's worked for us for years and will continue to guide us on our journey as a nation, and as we drive our car through the never-ending road of this adventure.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what do we do from here? How do we move forward?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll keep filming, photographing, and writing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You keep fighting the good fight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We'll meet somewhere along the road.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2011 07:45:43 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/275299-the-crest-of-the-u-turn</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/275299-the-crest-of-the-u-turn</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Weddings in a Doughnut Shop</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Succeeding is not really a life experience that does much good. Failing is a much more sobering and enlightening experience.&amp;quot; Michael Eisner&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's our last day in Portland, Oregon. We finishing up our time with a friend from college, Nate, who works in Portland now. As we catch up, we are told that we have to visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://voodoodoughnut.com&quot;&gt;Voodoo Doughnuts&lt;/a&gt;, a local staple that is world famous for their doughnuts. We decide that the chance to try world class doughnuts is something that we can't pass up.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drive up to the address of Voodoo Doughnuts, and the building is a bright pink, and the line is out the door. Apparently this place is good.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we make our way into the building, we are mesmerized by the menu choices: a Maple-Bacon Doughnut, a Captain Crunch topped doughnut, a Peanut-Butter glazed Oreo Doughnut. It's as if a college student took the junk food around their home and made doughnuts. These bad boys are delicious and boy are they popular.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another interesting aspect of Voodoo is that people can get &lt;a href=&quot;http://voodoodoughnut.com/weddings.php&quot;&gt;married in the building&lt;/a&gt;. We happened to be lucky enough to walk in on a couple finishing their vows. The people in line cheered, the crowd around them took photos, and they passed around champagne for the wedding party.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/voodoo wedding resized.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty surreal moment: we just happened to be in the right place at the right time. Which is pretty much what this whole trip has been hinging on. We've taken advantage of the opportunities in front of us and haven't looked back. This trip has been equal parts work, fun, relaxation, struggle, and growth. So as we bid farewell to Oregon, we wish it the best. It was beautiful and charming, and a nice chance for us to find kindness with JOIN, catch up with our friends who live there, and experience a new city in a fun way.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're in Port Orchard, WA now. Seattle this weekend.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to everyone soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State: Oregon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital: Salem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nickname: The Beaver State&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motto: Alis Volat Propriis (Latin. &amp;quot;She flies with her own wings&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flower: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Mahonia_aquifolium.jpg&quot;&gt;Oregon Grape&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flag:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8e/Mahonia_aquifolium.jpg/800px-Mahonia_aquifolium.jpg&quot; src=&quot;/Oregonflag.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2011 05:23:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/272486-weddings-in-a-doughnut-shop</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/272486-weddings-in-a-doughnut-shop</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Late Night Mission and Daily Growth in Portland, OR</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Compassion will cure more sins than condemnation&amp;quot; Henry Ward Beecher&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Portland is wet.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is cold, rainy, cloudy, and only really pleasant during the summer months. The rest of the time is a swing of weather from sunny and rainy, cloudy and rainy, and even snow.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But even with these factors, Portland still has one of the largest homeless populations in the the entire country. They sleep under bridges, camp out in community with each other, and suffer through their daily struggles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JOIN was created with the purpose of helping people out of their position. JOIN, however, initiates with a different mode of operation than most homeless services. Most places find their clients by the homeless coming to them. JOIN, on the other hand, goes to the homeless.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By day, JOIN operates as a place for the homeless to come in, grab a shower, do their laundry, access the internet, and socialize with each other. The only way the homeless can receive these services, however, is to &amp;quot;barter&amp;quot; with JOIN. They can do work for JOIN (making coffee, cleaning the office, cutting hair, etc.) and receive &amp;quot;barter time&amp;quot; which is used to take a shower, receive food and blankets, and a plethora of other services. These services are only provided from the hours of 10 am until 3 pm. This gives the homeless a place to stay during the day, but when they are done, they must move on. Throughout the day, case managers are meeting with their clients and helping them find a job, a home, and, in some cases, their family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At night, JOIN takes their mission to the streets. Instead of waiting for clients to walk into the office, members of JOIN go out into the city of Portland to find the homeless who are sleep under bridges, in tents, or on doorsteps. When they find them, they offer blankets, food and drink, and refer them to JOIN. That is how most of the clients come to JOIN: they were found on the streets. Volunteers and staff of JOIN find them and create a relationship that is beyond officer and client. They create a human relationship based on trust and understanding.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were given a chance to travel with Leo and Quinn, two staff members of JOIN, who drove us around Portland at night to deliver blankets, hot chocolate, and comfort to the homeless. While we traveled, we learned that Quinn had been doing this for 4 years and Leo for 14. They knew the route by heart and knew their clients by name. They spoke with the homeless first before offereing anything. They wanted to catch up and see how they were all doing during the wet months of Portland. They would give them blankets and hot chocolate after their words of comfort and promised to see them at JOIN's offices.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the entire trip, they always refered to the people we met as &amp;quot;friends.&amp;quot; And they meant it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, a friend is all we need to get help us get through a rough time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2011 18:20:08 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/269760-late-night-mission-and-daily-growth</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/269760-late-night-mission-and-daily-growth</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Pilgrim UCC and a Future YASC Site</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Why join the navy if you can be a pirate?&amp;quot; Steve Jobs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You would think that picking oranges would be a mundane task. While you twist them off, you just have to make sure that you don't drop it on the way to the basket. It's easy to accomplish and fun to do when the weather is nice. And this is where we found ourselves the moment we arrived at PIlgrim UCC.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we arrived to Pilgrim, we met with the Youth Group and were led to a member's home about 20 minutes away. She grows orange trees in her front yard. She has over 50 trees and nearly all of their branches have multiple oranges. They are large, ripe, and extra delicious.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;450&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; src=&quot;/orange.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Oranges&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The member didn't want to sell them, however. She wanted to give them away to a local food bank. Fruits are one of the last things the impoverished get for meals, so why not help out? The Youth Group from Pilgrim was one to help pick them. They were all fun-loving youth who took on the task with great passion. A perfect activity in the California sun.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;370&quot; src=&quot;/youth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;youth &quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the moment we arrived at Pilgrim UCC, we were exposed to how they view the world.&amp;nbsp;To their congregation, every little task, job, or activity can be used to help someone. They feel strongly about social justice and their congregation reflects it. They are active in their community's needs and desires. Whether it be writing to the local newspaper to voice concerns, organizing events to aid the poor, or raising awareness on AIDS/HIV, this congregation does it together.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/writing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And next year, Pilgrim will receive a volunteer corps of their own to help in their endeavors. Pilgrim UCC just voted to host a Young Adult Service Community (YASC) at their church. The YASC will be composed of four volunteers who live in intentional community, work with local agencies in their community, and promote the mission of Pilgrim UCC. We have covered groups like this before (See: Washington DC, Sahuarita, AZ, and Phoenix, AZ) and the groups will operate in the same manner.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Young Adults will be placed at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.interfaithservices.org/&quot;&gt;Interfaith Community Services&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.communityresourcecenter.org/&quot;&gt;Community Resource Center&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/site/equalityalliancesandiegocounty/our-mission&quot;&gt;Equality Alliance&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://justicesandiego.org/&quot;&gt;Justice Overcoming Boundaries&lt;/a&gt;. All of the organizations will utilize the Young Adults to complete tasks in community organizing and direct service. They will also take time to work with Pilgrim UCC in terms of leadership development. They will participate in Pilgrim's Youth Environmental Advocacy Engagement, Social Media Development/Training, and Worship Leadership. The work that they do with the church will be based on the Young Adult's interests, and Pilgrim's needs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A warning to future volunteers: You will fall in love with Pilgrim. Fast. They are welcoming, loving, and active. The entire atmosphere and attitude in Carlsbad is addictive so be prepared to have your world turned upside down in the best way possible. Good luck, and Godspeed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/cute.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Fri, 25 Feb 2011 06:57:18 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/262958-pilgrim-ucc-and-a-future-yasc</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/262958-pilgrim-ucc-and-a-future-yasc</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>A Visit with City of Refuge UCC</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;It is not only what we do, but also what we do not do, for which we are accountable.&amp;quot; - Moliere&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want theology? You can find it, but it won't be in any text.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you want a message of hope? We don't have words for that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have captured action. We have captured humanity. We have captured growth. We have seen people who have next to nothing donate their time, efforts, and talents to those who are tired, hungry, and cold. That's real theology. That's people who believe in something bigger than themselves. They serve their cause and serve others while serving themselves.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfrefuge.org/&quot;&gt;City of Refuge UCC&lt;/a&gt; in San Francisco, CA knows this attitude well. They apply it with all of their endeavors. Whether it be a food pantry on a cold Saturday morning, a support group for the transgendered community in San Francisco, or supporting an orphange in Zimbabwe, this church finds ways to serve others. You can see it in their volunteers and leaders as well. While filming, we were told that most of the volunteers who worked at the food pantry were originally the ones waiting in line for food. Then, they started to come to the City of Refuge for services and then started to help out with the food pantry. Now, they serve others who need the help more than they do. Because of the City of Refuge, people have found friendships throughout struggle, a family from the unexpected, and hope in a world that was once bleak.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They realize that theology is not something you talk about; rather, it is something that you &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We love that attitude. It's empowering. And highly addicting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We leave for Portland, OR tomorrow morning to visit with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joinpdx.com/&quot;&gt;JOIN&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in another state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Facts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name: California&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital: Sacramento&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nickname: The Golden State&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flower: &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:Kaldari_Eschscholzia_californica_01.jpg&quot;&gt;Golden Poppy&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Motto: &lt;em&gt;Eureka &lt;/em&gt;(Greek. &amp;quot;I have found it.&amp;quot;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State Flag:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;533&quot; src=&quot;/CaliforniaFlag.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2011 06:34:05 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/266242-a-visit-with-city-of-refuge</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/266242-a-visit-with-city-of-refuge</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Los Angeles, Fresno, and San Francisco, OH MY!</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;With our love, we could save the world&amp;quot; George Harrison&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the lack of updates... We've been awfully busy.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were in Carlsbad, CA, visiting with Pilgrim UCC. A more formal blog post will follow up with our visit there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We made a day trip to Los Angeles, California for President's Day. We met up with some friends who currently live there and saw the University of Southern California. We also visited Runyon Canyon. Runyon Canyon is a park inside the city of LA and has the best view of the skyline, homes, and surrounding areas. It was fantastic to see the LA community out and enjoying the sunshine in the park. Everyone out here is into fitness, which is as inspiring as it is demoralizing because they are all in much better shape than we are.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We were just in Fresno, CA. While there we were filming the Fresno Interdenominational Refugee Ministries (FIRM). Their services revolve around the needs of the refugee community in Fresno. They offer everything from ESL classes, to case management, and a preschool for refugee children. The cultural differences there are apparent the moment you walk in and you are drawn to everything they do. It's truly an addicting place to work. More to come on them as we press on with our projects.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate rice and bamboo yesterday for lunch. While we were eating, we found out that the bamboo was grown in North Carolina. The meal started to taste like irony after that.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We left for San Francisco this morning from Fresno and have arrived safely. We are working with the City of Refuge Ministries located in downtown San Francisco. When we arrived at our accommodations, we met with our contact and she told us about a support group for Transgendered Women that was occurring later tonight. We pulled our clothes upstairs then went to the ministries. While there, we interviewed two of the clients and heard their stories of growth, struggle, and activism throughout their lives. We'll be going there tomorrow morning as well to film. We're looking forward to this weekend.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we travel up California, it keeps getting colder. Good-bye t-shirts and flip-flops in winter months.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's all for now. We're getting up early tomorrow. Talk to everyone soon!&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 07:14:08 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/263773-los-angeles-fresno-and-san-francisco</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/263773-los-angeles-fresno-and-san-francisco</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Reflections and Fish Tacos</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Eat up&amp;quot; Jonathan's mother said.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We looked at the food presented to us with eager eyes. We were at the home of Mr. and Ms. Campos, the parents of Jonathan, our driver. in Ensenada, Mexico. His mom had cooked fish tenders on a pan, and placed them beside tomatoes, lettuce, pico de gallo, tortillas, salsa, and lemon juice. Fish tacos: a classic meal from Ensenada, a Mexican coastal town. We had been on a long trip down to the city so the meal in front of us was welcomed by our hungry stomachs. We sat around the table with five others, Jonathan, his mother, father, sister, and Carlos, our guide. Spanish was their native language, so they spoke freely in Spanish. While we didn't understand Spanish, we appreciated the quiet silence of being removed from the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we started our fish taco cadence, our minds wandered back to the events of the day. We had seen, and had yet to process, a lot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We drove over the border, without incident, and met with Tony, a local minister. He was a friend of Carlos and would be with us as we worked in Tijuana. We traveled to La Casa de las Pobres (The House of the Poor), which gives out food packages of rice and beans everyday to anyone who wants for it. They also provide medical services to anyone who wants it. These services are provided by nuns who have devoted their lives to bettering the lives of others. And in Tijuana, that's everyone. Everyone needs food, money, a job, and a comfort that they can provide for their families later. While La Casa cannot help with many of those things, they can at least provide food.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The numbers of people receiving services has only increased. The clinic has seen an influx of patients, the kitchen more mouths to feed, and the community does not show any sign of progress.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We capture what we can and move on. Tony takes us to the place where he works, Las Memorias. Las Memorias is a clinic for anyone with HIV/AIDS who cannot afford the medical care needed for the virus, the only one like it in Tijuana and all of Mexico. They have no staff members, because patients that are well enough to care for others do so. The clinic is staffed completely by volunteers. While we are there, we see mothers with their children. These children, born at the clinic, have the same virus as their mother. Tony takes us back to the intensive care room in the back of the clinic. While there, we saw a man who had come into the clinic just last night. His mother was sitting beside his bed, watching as the volunteer helped with his treatment.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her son was in poor health. He was unresponsive to any communication.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We stepped away from the scene... It was too much to bear.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we left Las Memorias, Carlos asked us what we thought about this place.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat in silence before responding that we could not process the events that we had just seen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We sat in front of our fish tacos, satisfied with our meal and hospitality, but not with what we saw.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even as we write this, four days removed from the experience it, we cannot think of a way to process it. The immersion into Mexico was raw, real, and something that we will never forget.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notes:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're currently in Carlsbad, CA, visiting with Pilgrim UCC. Our next stop is in Fresno, CA. We arrive there on Tuesday.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We got our oil changed just last month, and because of our driving, we now have to change it again. Our car has been good to us though.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All for now. Bed time.&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 08:36:54 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/259974-reflections-and-fish-tacos</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/259974-reflections-and-fish-tacos</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Shanty Towns, Smoke, and Toxic Water</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;In Mexico, you have death very close. That's true for all human beings because it's a part of life, but in Mexico, death can be found in many things.&amp;quot; Gael Garcia Bernal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing you notice is the smell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you step out of your vehicle and lay your eyes on the shanty town neighborhood of Chilpancingo in Tijuana, the first thing you notice is the smell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is toxic.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And it is coming from their water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Toxic-Water.png&quot; alt=&quot;Toxic Water&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you recover from the rancid smell of the neighborhood's water source, you look around and discover that the neighborhood of Chilpancingo can hardly be called a neighborhood at all. It's more like a collection of wooden walls that people sleep in. These homes stretch on for miles.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Chilpancingo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Look over there!&amp;quot; Carlos Correa, our guide and program director for Centro Romero, points. &amp;quot;Someone is burning something.&amp;quot; He says with disdain.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;What do you think they are burning?&amp;quot; Jonathan, our 22 year old driver, asks.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Tires, chemicals, waste...&amp;quot; Carlos says with resignation. &amp;quot;Whatever it is, it's toxic.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Black Smoke redux.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;This is nothing new.&amp;quot; Carlos continues. &amp;quot;Most of these people work in the factory right up the road. If the factory doesn't want to get rid of the waste, they pass it on to their employees to destroy or use them. This is a weekly occurrence.&amp;quot;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how some people in Tijuana live. They live in extreme conditions of poverty, their homes are deteriorated, their health is poor, and&amp;nbsp;their children have little chance of a better life. But this is how life is in Tijuana, the border city that is at the northern and western most point of Mexico, sharing a border with California. It is an epicenter of poverty and corruption. For Carlos, however, this is where his mission lies.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centro Romero is an organization that facilitates educational-transformational immersion seminars along the border focusing on issues of globalization, economic policies, immigration, and community empowerment. One of the services that Centro Romero provides is an immersion experience for Americans that want to see how people live on the other side of the border. Participants get to see for themselves the lifestyle that many Mexicans live in. No spin, no policy, just a raw in-your-face experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're going to experience a part of that immersion.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow, we will be driving back into Mexico. We will be staying in the night in Ensenada, Mexico. It's south of Tijuana and Jonathan's mother lives there. After lots of filming, we'll head back to Tijuana and then return to the US. You shouldn't expect an update from us until we get back to the US on Friday.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/Trash in Chilpancingo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once we felt as if we had enough footage, we crossed back over the bridge leading into Chilpancingo. The water that was previously black was now brown. Bubbles had started forming where the water was stagnant, a sign of a chemical reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As we pressed on, we noticed a small girl. She was with her family, but she had found something to distract her while adults chatted. She walked to the river and started to pick up a few rocks on the way. She would need this for her own ammunition. She stopped, set her body, and started to throw rocks into the toxic river.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/A Child Fights Back.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep fighting, kid.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2011 08:32:21 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/256827-shanty-towns-smoke-and-toxic-water</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/256827-shanty-towns-smoke-and-toxic-water</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>San Ysidro: Day 1. We get kicked out of a strip mall. </title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;I write-down to speak-up&amp;quot; MK Asante Jr.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Monday, we arrived in San Ysidro, a neighborhood south of downtown San Diego. We met with Carlos Correa, the program director of Centro Romero. We met, settled down, and discussed our schedule.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up on Tuesday and got to work immediately. We wanted to film the border fence that is at the point of entry for Interstate 5 in San Ysidro, CA. The closest we could get to the fence was at a strip mall called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/outlets/outlet.asp?id=76&quot;&gt;Las Americas Outlets&lt;/a&gt;. The parking lot of the Outlet ends and the fence begins. Perfect. We started to film on the property of this strip mall. The juxtaposition of overpriced commercialism against the eye-soreof a fence was poetic. We filmed great footage there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or rather, we HAD great footage there.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When we started to film, we were stopped by head of security for the Outlet, Phillip. All well and good. It was their property, so they wanted to know what were doing and filming. We explained our project and purpose of our footage. After a brief conversation with Phillip and Vanessa, manager of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/outlets/outlet.asp?id=76&quot;&gt;Las Americas Outlets&lt;/a&gt;, they told us they had to run our filming by Corporate, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/&quot;&gt;Premium Outlets&lt;/a&gt;. So we ran over to their offices and explained our project once more. They ran it by corporate offices and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/&quot;&gt;Premium Outlets&lt;/a&gt; called us personally. We explained the project to them. Once they had another conversation with Vanessa, she came in and stated that we could not film on their property. We asked if we could just capture the border fence and not the store fronts. She said that we could not. Her reasoning was that corporate &amp;quot;does not want to be associated with border issues.&amp;quot; With that, we were escorted off the premises by Phillip.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This matter was handled with great professionalism by both Phillip and Vanessa. We cannot thank them enough for being understanding with us and our project. We were 100% cooperative with their questions and demands. While they said nothing about the footage that we had already captured, we won't release the footage we captured today from the outlet. We could use the footage, the film, the pictures etc. of the fence and you wouldn't be able to tell the difference. But we aren't going to use them.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the right thing to do.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;THAT SAID, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/outlets/outlet.asp?id=76&quot;&gt;Las Americas Outlets&lt;/a&gt;, an extension of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.premiumoutlets.com/&quot;&gt;Premium Outlets&lt;/a&gt;, will always be associated with the border. Not just border issues, but the border itself. Whenever you shop at the outlet, you see the border. You turn the corner at Nike Factory store, you see the huge fence. You leave Coach, you see the traffic flooding into customs. You exit Old Navy, and Border Patrol cars can be seen.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seems as if the location is somewhat counterproductive to not being associated with the border.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What makes the situation that much more ridiculous is that we went to the point of entry immediately after geting escorted off of a strip mall (a pretty embarrassing feat, mind you). When we arrived at customs, we asked the officers there if we could film the traffic flowing in and out of the border. They told us we could, but only if we didn't capture any officers and if we did it quickly. We did so and all parties were satisfied.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After leaving customs, we visited two extra sites, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicanoparksandiego.com/&quot;&gt;Chicano Park&lt;/a&gt; and Friendship Park. Chicano Park's history is fantastic and you should &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicanoparksandiego.com/&quot;&gt;read up on their history&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chicanoparksandiego.com/&quot;&gt;Right now&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Friendship Park, however, is different. It's on the beach and is the southernmost point in California. It's where the fence ends and were relatives could met, exchange contacts, and even participate in Yoga classes. When we arrived at the park, cars couldn't drive through, so we had to walk a mile and a half just to get out there. When we got out there, we found that Friendship Park had been separated, due to an executive order from President Bush. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2008/10/22/world/americas/22iht-22border.17155357.html&quot;&gt;Read up about it here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We've got a busy few days ahead of us. Tomorrow we're going into Tijuana and coming back into the US. On Thursday, we're going into Tijuana and then staying the night and coming back on Friday to the US.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apologies for the brief writing. It's late and we have to get up early. Writing would be better if we had more time to think and reflect but we don't.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talk to everyone soon!&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 09:24:31 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/255945-san-ysidro-day-1-we-get</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/255945-san-ysidro-day-1-we-get</link>
        </item>
        
        <item>
          <title>Mid-Year Retreat: Gaining Brothers and Sisters from all walks of Life</title>
          <description>
            
            &lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;Sometimes, the most urgent thing you can do is take a complete rest.&amp;quot; Ashleigh Brilliant&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you read our last blog closely, you noticed that we were gone from Wednesday until Sunday (February 9th until the 13th) on the Mid-Year Volunteer Retreat for the Partners in Service Volunteers. We traveled by plane to San Antonio TX, and then took a 40 minute drive to Sunset Falls Retreat center in New Braufells, TX. After a delay in Phoenix, changing a connecting flight in Dallas-Fort Worth, and finding ways to waste time on a 3 hour layover, we finally arrived in San Antonio. We were picked up at the airport and shared the ride out to the retreat center with David, a Ukrainian volunteer from Hopewell Farms. David was the first volunteer that we met on this trip at Hopewell Farms so it was nice to catch up with him and see how much he had grown over his time in the states. &amp;nbsp;We arrived at the retreat center at 9:00 Central Time.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retreat's theme concerned the Sabbath and how to honor it. And this theme could not come at a better time. We had our discussions lead by Reverend Daniel Moser and we also participated by sharing about our volunteer experiences at our sites. We revisited many of the themes that we've covered already: we discussed how homelessness can be overcome with help, how mental illness can be a spring board for success, how disaster victims need our immediate help, and how border issues are among the most tragic stories we've heard. While we discussed our projects, we each gained a glimpse into the work that all of the volunteers are doing across the United States.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volunteers themselves are equally as incredible. The majority of them (nearly 3/4ths) are German citizens who are volunteering abroad for one year (Two others were Belgian and one other was Ukrainian).&amp;nbsp;While it was different to hear another language besides English, we knew we were in the presence of good people due to their sincerity. Each of the foreign volunteers brought kindness, trust, and hope into the retreat as we grew our friendships beyond that of just service. As the week progressed, we became brothers and sisters with each other. We talked about everything from our futures, politics, and sports. We played games, shared meals, swapped rooms... everything that camp should be we did it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for lack of time, and focus, (we have a drive to San Diego tomorrow), let's just give you the highlights of the trip in note form:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We saw many volunteers at the retreat that we had already seen on this trip (Kai, Kevin, and Robin from St. Louis; Nelson from Lancaster, Yannick from Massachusetts), met volunteers that we would meet (Keith in Portland, Hannah in Seattle, Josef and Hanna in Iowa) and met others that we wouldn't have had the chance to meet otherwise (Niklaus, Wadim, Andre, and many many others).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ran three times during the retreat. We had to exercise a little bit during camp. We don't say this to feel good about ourselves, we say it because we were beat every time by our fellow runners.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone in Germany has played &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mafia_(party_game)&quot;&gt;this game&lt;/a&gt; and is highly skilled at it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you get right down to it, there isn't much difference between a 20 something from Europe and a 20 something from America.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We visited the Alamo in San Antonio. Great chance to see a part of Texas and US History.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ate very well on this retreat. We had French Toast in the morning, delicious camp lunches and dinners, and oranges and apples for lecture snacks. It was awesome.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had an exercise where we walked around the campsite for 30 minutes in complete silence. While the exercise was fulfilling, Max found himself playing a game on large rocks. No one is surprised.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This picture makes all of us laugh to no end.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;467&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; src=&quot;/Nelson and Julien.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To everyone on the retreat: Thank you for making it one of the best few days of this trip. We came as twins, and left with more brothers and sisters than we know what to do with. We'll see you all in the future, whether it be in the states or in Europe. But we promise we'll see you all again.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img height=&quot;467&quot; width=&quot;700&quot; src=&quot;/Retreat Group.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
          </description>
          <pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2011 07:26:35 GMT</pubDate>
          <guid>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/254068-mid-year-retreat-gaining-brothers-and-sisters</guid>
          <link>http://www.twinmaps.com/post/254068-mid-year-retreat-gaining-brothers-and-sisters</link>
        </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>